Guide to the Dorothy Norman Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Pre-1990 Acquisitions, 1908-1983; 2; 25.25; 28 boxes
  - Alfred Stieglitz Correspondence
    - Wright, Richard. Photograph for the Stieglitz Memorial Portfolio, undated (Box 82)
    - Envelope of return receipts & list of people whose letters from Stieglitz were returned after copying, undated (Box 82)
  - Literary Manuscripts
    Arranged alphabetically by author.
    Literary Manuscripts contains essays, poems, and other writings in autograph manuscript, typescript, and printed materials, that were submitted to or collected by Dorothy Norman for the publication Twice A Year, including the Alfred Stieglitz issue of that journal.
    - Abrams, Ray. "The Conscientious Objector in the World War", undated (Box 83)
    - Adler, Miriam. "The Witnesses", undated (Box 83)
    - Alberti, Rafael. "Words for Frederico", undated (Box 83)
    - Alexander, Norman. Untitled poem, undated (Box 83)
    - Americans for Democratic Action. "Foreign Policy", 1948 February 29 (Box 83)
    - Amram, Emilie. Untitled, undated (Box 83)
    - Anand, Mulk Raj. Private Life of an Indian Prince, undated (Box 83)
    - Anderson, Edith. "Loretta", 1947 July 1929 (Box 83)
    - Anderson, Sherwood. "The Dance is On", [1940] (Box 83)
    - Anderson, Richard. "Chant of Myself", undated (Box 83)
    - Arata, Oliver. "Crispus Attucks", 1945, undated (Box 83)
    - Ascoli, Max. "The World Civil War", undated (Box 83)
    - Bach, Julian. "The Human Guinea Pigs", undated (Box 83)
    - Bailyn, Bernard. "Death in the Higher Life", undated (Box 83)
    - Baldwin, Roger N. (Roger Nash). "Civil Liberties", undated (Box 83)
    - Barr, Alfred. Eulogy to Alfred Stieglitz, 1947 February 3 (Box 83)
    - Batlivala, Bhicoo. "Civil Liberties in India", undated (Box 83)
    - Bauer, Otto. Die illegale Partei, 1939 (Box 83)
    - Beam, Lura. "Georgia O'Keeffe", 1938 January 18 (Box 83)
    - Beard, Mary Ritter. Untitled, undated (Box 83)
    - Beauvoir, Simone de. "Freedom and Liberation", 1948 (Box 83)
    - Beauvoir, Simone de. "Literature and Metaphysics", undated (Box 83)
    - Beck, Maximilian. "Philosophie und Politik", undated (Box 83)
    - Beckgran, Robert. Mr. Li's Net From Heaven, undated (Box 83)
    - Beecher, John. "Here I Stand", 1941, undated; 2 (Box 83)
    - Beecher, John. Poems, 1940-1941, undated; 2 (Box 83)
    - Beecher, John. "This Our Exile", 1947 June 21 (Box 83)
    - Beecher, Virginia. "Out of the Death the Flower Small Come", undated (Box 83)
    - Benchley, Nathaniel. "Red Propaganda in Romeo and Juliet", 1947 November 2 (Box 83)
    - Bernstein, Henri. "In Defense of Franco-American Friendship", 1943 October 28 (Box 83)
    - Black, Hugo L. "Address of Mr. Justice Hugo L. Black To Be Delivered Before the Colorado Bar Association at Colorado Springs, September 12, 1941, at 8 P.M.", 1941 September 13 (Box 83)
    - Blok, A. (Aleksandr). Excerpts from his diaries, undated (Box 83)
    - Bloch, Ernst. "Man & Music", 1933, undated (Box 83)
    - Bloch, Ernst. "Three Concerts of Chamber Music", 1937 December (Box 83)
    - Bloch, Ernst. "Writers in Exile", 1939 June 4 (Box 83)
    - Blum, Jérome. "Notes", undated (Box 83)
    - Borgese, Giuseppe Antonio. Unsorted writings, 1945, undated (Box 83)
    - Bourne, Randolph. Transcripts of letters, 1938, undated (Box 83)
    - Bovey, John. "Death in Venice: Structure and Image", undated (Box 83)
    - Bowles, Jane. "In the Summer House", 1953 (Box 83)
    - Brant, Irving. "The Press and Political Leadership", undated (Box 83)
    - Brant, Irving. "The Struggle for Civil Liberties", 1937? (Box 83)
    - Brecht, Bertolt. "Five Obstacles to Writing the Truth," translated by Richard Winston, undated (Box 83)
    - Breit, Harvey. Poems, undated (Box 83)
    - Breit, Harvey. "A Visit With Arthur Koestler", undated (Box 83)
    - Breton, André & Masson, André. "Le dialogue créole", undated (Box 83)
    - Brett, Dorothy. Untitled, 1946, undated (Box 83)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck. "Primary Literature and Coterie-Literature", undated (Box 84)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck. "The Reading of Melville", undated (Box 84)
    - Brown, John. "The Drama of Existentialist Man", undated (Box 84)
    - Brown, John. "Variations on a Theme", undated (Box 84)
    - Bryan, A. W., Jr. Untitled, undated (Box 84)
    - Bryan, William, Jr. "Stieglitz", undated (Box 84)
    - Bryher. "The Crisis: September", undate (Box 84)
    - Bryner, Edna. "Members One of Another", undated (Box 84)
    - Calas, Nicolas. "Transforming the Past", undated (Box 84)
    - Camus, Albert. "The Human Crisis", undated (Box 84)
    - Camus, Albert. "Kirilov", undated (Box 84)
    - Camus, Albert. "Spain", undated (Box 84)
    - Camus, Albert. "We Too Are Murderers", undated (Box 84)
    - Cartier-Bresson, Henri. Untitled, undated (Box 84)
    - Cayton, Horace. "Frightened Children of Frightened Parents", 1945 February 22 (Box 84)
    - Chiaromonte, Nicola. "G. A. Borgese, Fascism and the Italian Nation," translated by Frances Keene, 1939, undated (Box 84)
    - Clark, Grenville. "The Limits of Free Expression", 1939 (Box 84)
    - Claudel, Paul. "High Noon", undated (Box 84)
    - Clurman, Harold. "Soviet Diary", undated (Box 84)
    - Clurman, Harold. "Beautiful Letters", undated (Box 84)
    - Cocteau, Jean. Le Fantôme de Marseille, 1936 (Box 84)
    - Cohen, Elie E. "Democracy, Defense, and Discrimination", undated (Box 84)
    - Commager, Henry Steele. "The United States; Expansion and Freedom", undated (Box 84)
    - Coomaraswamy, Ananda K. (Ananda Kentish). "The Traditional Conception of Ideal Portraiture", undated (Box 84)
    - Copland, Aaron. "The Musical Scene Changes", undated (Box 84)
    - Couch, W. S. "What the Negro Wants", undated (Box 84)
    - Crane, Hart. Excerpts from letters to Alfred Stieglitz, undated (Box 84)
    - Crippen, Harlan R. (Harlan Robert). "Notes from a Soldier's Journal", undated (Box 84)
    - Crippen, Harlan R. (Harlan Robert). "Fields and Years", undated (Box 84)
    - Crippen, Harlan R. (Harlan Robert). "Love, Legend, and History", undated (Box 84)
    - Cummings, E. E. (Edward Estlin). "What About It?", undated (Box 84)
    - Cunard, Nancy. "Ballad of the Two Wars", undated (Box 84)
    - Curtiss, Thomas Quinn. "Ernst Toller", undated (Box 84)
    - Davenport, Walter. "Race Riots Coming", 1943 September 18 (Box 84)
    - Davidson, Gustav. "The Most Tragic Story in the Annals of Mathematics: the Life of Evariste Galois", undated (Box 84)
    - Davidson, Gustav. Poems, undated (Box 84)
    - Davidson, Peggy. "Jealousy", 1937 August 11 (Box 84)
    - Decour, Jacques. "Unedited Memorandum", 1938 September 26 (Box 84)
    - Demuth, Charles. "Lighthouse and Fog", undated (Box 84)
    - De Sanctis, Francesco. "The Character of Dante and his Utopia," translated by Elio Gianturco, undated (Box 84)
    - Dodson, Owen. "Color, U.S.A.", undated (Box 84)
    - Douglas, Gilean. "Solace for Eternity", undated (Box 84)
    - Dove, Arthur Garfield. "The 20th Century Limited, Or the Train Left Without Them", undated (Box 84)
    - Dreiser, Theodore. "Appearance and Reality", 1933-1946, undated (Box 84)
    - Dreiser, Theodore. "The Dawn Is in the East", undated (Box 84)
    - Droth, Andrew. Eulogy to Alfred Stieglitz, undated (Box 84)
    - Duckett, Alfred. Poems, undated (Box 84)
    - Durrell, Laurence. "The Prince and Hamlet", 1937 Januray 14 (Box 84)
    - Duryee, Mary Ballard. "A Jewish Girl Talks With Her Lover", undated (Box 84)
    - Eastman, Daniel. "Issues Affecting Civil Liberty", undated (Box 84)
    - Einstein, Albert. "Science and Religion", undated (Box 84)
    - Einstein, Albert. "Hearing Before the Anglo-American Committee of Inquiry, Washington, D. C.", 1946 January 11 (Box 84)
    - Einstein, William. "Virtues Reward", undated (Box 84)
    - Ellis, Havelock. "Nationalism and Peace", undated (Box 84)
    - Elmslie, George Grant. "Chicago School of Architecture: Its Inheritance and Bequest", 1940 December (Box 84)
    - Enters, Angna. "The Arts of Iran, Ancient Persia and Bagdad", 1938 August (Box 84)
    - Enters, Angna. "From Another World", 1940 (Box 84)
    - Enters, Angna. "Love Possessed Juana", 1939 (Box 84)
      Includes agreement between the author and Dorothy Norman for the publication of the play.
    - Enters, Angna. "Notes From My Journal", undated (Box 84)
    - Enters, Angna. "What I Like in Music", 1940 (Box 84)
      Includes signature stamp.
    - Enters, Angna. "Working in Three Arts", undated (Box 84)
    - Enters, Angna. Unsorted writings, undated (Box 84)
    - Everson, William. "One Born Of This Time", undated (Box 84)
    - Everson, William. "Two Poems", undated (Box 84)
    - Faure, Élie. "The Cult of Bigness", undated (Box 84)
    - Faure, Élie. "Contemporary French Art", undated (Box 84)
    - Feibleman, James. "Charles S. Peirce: A Philosophy for America", undated (Box 84)
    - Feibleman, James. "Tale of the Island Shopkeeper", undated (Box 84)
    - Feibleman, James. Poems, undated (Box 84)
    - Feibleman, James. "Toward the Recovery of Giambattista Vico", undated (Box 84)
    - Feibleman, James. "The Unlimited Community", undated (Box 84)
    - Fischel, Marguerite. Poems, 1942 (Box 84)
      Includes music scores.
    - Fleisch, Phillipp. Poems, undated (Box 84)
    - Fischer, Louis. Unsorted writings, 1948, undated (Box 84)
    - Flint, Ralph. "Prize Song", undated (Box 84)
    - Foote, Alvin. Poems, undated (Box 84)
    - Fraenkel, Michael. "Journal - 1940", undated (Box 85)
    - Fraenkel, Osmond K. (Osmond Kessler). "Our Bill of Rights", undated (Box 85)
    - Frank, John P. (John Paul). "Holmes and Brandeis: Civil Rights, 1946", 1949 (Box 85)
    - Frank, Waldo David. Untitled, undated (Box 85)
    - Frankenberg, Lloyd. "To Ignazio Silone", undated (Box 85)
    - Frankenberg, Lloyd. "The Legend of Alfred Stieglitz", undated (Box 85)
    - Frankenberg, Lloyd. "The Poetry of E. E. Cummings", 1948, undated (Box 85)
    - Frankfurter, Felix. Unsorted writings, undated (Box 85)
    - Frazier, Winnifred. "A Day in Heaven", 1942 August 19 (Box 85)
    - Freeman, Joseph. "The Flight from Hell", undated (Box 85)
    - Fried, John H. E. "Democratic Tools in Fascist Hands", undated (Box 85)
    - Fried, Hans. "Who Shall Mould the Vision of Our Time", undated (Box 85)
    - Fry, Christopher. "The First Act of the Firstborn", undated (Box 85)
    - Fry, Christopher. Poems, 1939 (Box 85)
    - Gide, André. "Oscar Wilde", 1941 (Box 85)
    - Gittelson, Bernard. "Blue Print for Action", undated (Box 85)
    - Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von. "Venetian Epigrams", undated (Box 85)
    - Goldman, Emma. Untitled, 1938 April 8 (Box 85)
    - Goll, Claire. "Rainer Maria Rilke and Women", undate (Box 85)
    - Goodman, Ezra. Poems, undated (Box 85)
    - Goodwin, Philip. Eulogy to Alfred Stieglitz, 1946 October 1 (Box 85)
    - Graf, Oskar Maria. "The Penitent", undated (Box 85)
    - Graf, Oskar Maria. "The Unvanquished", undated (Box 85)
    - Greenberg, Samuel. Poems, undated (Box 85)
    - Greer, Scott. Poems, undated (Box 85)
    - Gremley, William. "A Letter to the Stars and Stripes", 1945 August 29 (Box 85)
    - Grierson, René. "Individualism", undated (Box 85)
    - Gronowicz, Antoni. "A Sterilized Prophet in Nazi Germany", undated (Box 85)
    - Grossberg, Paul. "On a Mountain in America", 1941? (Box 85)
    - Grosz, George. Poems, undated (Box 85)
    - Guilloux, Louis. "Les réfugiés trahis", undated (Box 85)
    - Gutman, Ernest. Untitled, undated (Box 85)
    - Hapgood, Norman. "On Intolerance", undated (Box 85)
    - Hapgood, Norman. "What is an Anarchist?", undated (Box 85)
    - Harper, Carol Ely. "Sunday Morning Service", undated (Box 85)
    - Harris, Roy. "Our Musical Scene in Two Tones", undated (Box 85)
    - Hartman, Bertram & Gusta. Untitled, undated (Box 85)
    - Hartley, Marsden. Untitled, undated (Box 85)
    - Hasegawa, Saburō. "Abstract Art in Japan", undated (Box 85)
    - Hasegawa, Saburō. "Belief", 1952 (Box 85)
    - Hasegawa, Saburō. "Tea-Ism", undated (Box 85)
    - Haydon, Stuart. "Will the San Francisco Charter Work?", undated (Box 85)
    - Hayman, Lee Richard. "Incident Via Victory", undated (Box 85)
    - Heppenstall, Rayner. "Some in White Beds, With Faces Round Them", undated (Box 85)
    - Herbert, George. "Peace", undated (Box 85)
    - Heyman, Ruth. Untitled, undated (Box 85)
    - Hiebel, Frederick. "Novalis", undated (Box 85)
    - Hindus, Milton. "Politics", undated (Box 85)
    - Hölderlin, Friedrich. "Hyperion," translated by Carol North Valhope, undated (Box 85)
    - Hofmannsthal, Hugo von. "Pathways and Encounters", undated (Box 85)
    - Holbrook, Doris. "My Wish-Running", undated (Box 85)
    - Holbrook, Sabra. "Report on the Summer School Project Operated by Youthbuilders, Inc.", 1943 August (Box 85)
    - Holmes, John Haynes. "Peace", 1938 March 1 (Box 85)
    - Honig, Edwin. "Garcia Lorca's Folk Tragedies", 1943 (Box 85)
    - Horváth, Ödön von. "Figaro Gets a Divorce", undated (Box 85)
    - Houston, Peyton. "Variations Upon a Theme of Heraclitus", undated (Box 85)
    - Ignatow, David. Poems, undated (Box 85)
    - Irwin, Theodore. "Review of the Year", undated (Box 85)
    - Ives, Charles. "From: Notes", 1934 (Box 85)
    - Jacobsen, Louise. "The Minneapolis Sedition Case", undated (Box 85)
    - James, Earle K. "Federation in Latin America", undated (Box 85)
    - James, Rebecca Salsbury. Eulogy to Alfred Stieglitz, undate (Box 85)
    - Janis, Sidney. They Taught Themselves, 1942 (Box 85)
      Includes publicity release.
    - Jay, William. "Hitler and Communism", undated (Box 85)
    - Jay, William. "A Poet's Prediction", 1939 June 3 (Box 85)
    - Jewell, Edward Alden. Two newspaper articles on Alfred Stieglitz, 1946 (Box 85)
    - Johnson, Ernest E. "The Negro's Legislative Program", 1945 February 4 (Box 85)
    - Johnston, Dudley. "Obituary", 1946 August (Box 85)
    - Jones, S. Beryl. "Sacrifice Without Redemption", undated (Box 85)
    - Joseph, J. Calder (John Calder). Poems, undated (Box 85)
    - Josephson, Matthew. Untitled, undated (Box 85)
    - Joyce, James. Finnegan's Wake, undated (Box 85)
    - Kafka, Franz. Translations of parables and short stories, undated (Box 85)
    - Kahler, Erich. "The German Character in the History of Europe", undated (Box 85)
    - Kahn, Hannah. "The Moving Stream", undated (Box 85)
    - Kalonyme, Louis. "A Room for Everyone", undated (Box 85)
    - Kazin, Alfred. "War, Education, and People", undated (Box 85)
    - Keene, Frances. "Fear", undated (Box 85)
    - Keene, Frances. "Memorandum on Italy", 1943 (Box 85)
    - Keene, Frances. Poems, undated (Box 85)
    - Keene, Frances. Unsorted writings, undated (Box 85)
    - Kingdon, Frank. "Compact Definitions of Democracy, Socialism, Communism and Fascism", 1939 (Box 85)
    - Konvitz, Milton R. (Milton Ridvas). "Civil Liberties in the Supreme Court, 1943 and 1944", undated (Box 85)
    - Konvitz, Milton R. (Milton Ridvas). "The Nature of Bronson Alcott", 1947 July 10 (Box 85)
    - Kreymborg, Alfred. "Time Exposure", undated (Box 85)
    - Kuniholm, Stanley. "From: The Enchanted Castle", undated (Box 85)
    - Lachaise, Gaston. "A Comment On My Sculpture", undated (Box 85)
    - Lachaise, Isabel. Untitled, undated (Box 85)
    - Lamb, Beatrice. "From: A Letter to X", undated (Box 85)
    - Lang, Daniel. "It's Hard to Recant", undated (Box 85)
    - Latzko, Andreas. "The Double Patriot," translated by Ralph Manheim, undated (Box 85)
    - L'Engle, Madeleine. "From a City Boarding House", undated (Box 85)
    - Léon, Felipe. "The Axe," translated by Waldo Frank, undated (Box 85)
    - Léon, Felipe. "Wings and Humps: Or The King Fool," translated by Waldo Frank, undated (Box 85)
    - Lerner, Max. "Randolph Bourne and Two Generations", undated (Box 85)
    - Lescaze, Mary Hughes. "For Stieglitz", undated (Box 85)
    - Lescaze, William. "On Stieglitz", undated (Box 85)
    - Levi, Carlo. "Interview", 1947 (Box 85)
    - Leyda, Jay. "The Army of the Potomac Entertains a Poet", undated (Box 85)
    - Lincoln, Abraham. "From: Speech at Chicago - July 4, 1858", undated (Box 86)
      Includes "If We Wish To Be Free...", edited by Bernard Smith, with a foreword by Allan Nevins.
    - López-Rey y Arrojo, José. "Introduction to El Greco", undated (Box 86)
    - Lorca, Frederico Garcia. Poems, undated (Box 86)
    - Low, A. Ritchie. "Sermons Are Not Enough", undated (Box 86)
    - Lyons, Edward. "From the City of Blazing Darkness", undated (Box 86)
    - Lyons, Edward. "The Jick Incident", undated (Box 86)
    - Lyons, Edward. "Plea", 1940 March 12 (Box 86)
    - Macdonald, Dwight. "War Is the Issue", undated (Box 86)
    - Macdonald-Wright, Stanton. Eulogy to Alfred Stieglitz, undated (Box 86)
    - MacDuffie, Marshall. "Civil Liberties Are What You Make Them", undated (Box 86)
    - Madison, Charles. "The Abolition Movement", undated (Box 86)
    - Magny, Claude-Edmonde. "Introduction to the Reading of Don Passos", 1946, undated (Box 86)
    - Maier, Joseph & Jaari, Sendert. "These Were the Supermen", 1946 (Box 86)
    - Malraux, André. Man's Hope, 1938 November 3 (Box 86)
    - Malraux, André. Unsorted writings, undated (Box 86)
    - Mani, A. D. "Gentlemen Meet Uncle Sam", undated (Box 86)
    - Mann, Klaus. "The Aims", undated (Box 86)
    - Mann, Klaus. "Europe - America", undated (Box 86)
    - Mann, Thomas. Essays and diary entries, undated (Box 86)
    - Manning, Hugo. Poems, undated (Box 86)
    - Marc, Franz. "Letters", undated (Box 86)
    - Marin, John. "A Few Notes", undated (Box 86)
      Includes unsorted notes, excerpts from letters to Alfred Stieglitz, and John Marin: the Man and His Work by E. M. Benson.
    - Matisse, Henri. "Notes by a Painter", undated (Box 86)
    - Mayer, Morris & Fritz. "Two Events", undated (Box 86)
    - McBride, Henry. "A Note on Stieglitz", 1932, undated (Box 86)
    - McCausland, Elizabeth. Untitled, 1947, undated (Box 86)
    - McLane, Charles. "Commencement Speech, Dartmouth College", undated (Box 86)
    - McManis, Jack. "To Stieglitz", undated (Box 86)
    - Mead, Margaret. "Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion", undated (Box 86)
    - Mellquist, Jerome. "Eulogy to Paul Rosenfeld", circa 1946 (Box 86)
    - Mellquist, Jerome. Excerpt from letter, 1946 August 6 (Box 86)
    - Mellquist, Jerome. "The Iron Grip of Stieglitz", undated (Box 86)
    - Mellquist, Jerome. Untitled, undated (Box 86)
    - Merriam, Eve. "The Guy", undated (Box 86)
    - Messer, Mary. "Words Are Too Loud", undated (Box 86)
    - Milgram, Morris. "Involuntary Servitude in Florida", undated (Box 86)
    - Milgram, Morris. "The Poll Tax and the White Primary", 1943 January 1 (Box 86)
    - Miller, Arthur. "All My Sons", 1947 (Box 86)
    - Miller, Arthur. "Balzac", 1940 (Box 86)
    - Miller, Henry. "Balzac and His Double", undated (Box 86)
    - Miller, Henry. "An Open Letter To All and Sundry", undated (Box 86)
    - Miller, Henry. Unsorted writings, undated (Box 86)
    - Milliken, William. "Alfred Stieglitz, Photographer An Appreciation", undated (Box 86)
    - Moore, Marianne. Eulogy to Alfred Stieglitz, undated (Box 86)
    - Moore, Nicholas. "The Imaginative", undated (Box 86)
    - More, Herman. Untitled, undated (Box 86)
    - Morris, Wright. "Mr. Shults", undated (Box 86)
    - Mullins, Helene. "Self-Rhythm", undated (Box 86)
    - Mumford, Lewis. Unsorted writings, undated (Box 86)
    - Murphy, Frank. "In Defense of Democracy", undated (Box 86)
    - Murray, James E. "Statement of Senator James E. Murray Upon Introduction of the Full Employment Bill of 1945", 1945 January 22 (Box 86)
    - Murray, Pauli. "The Right to Equal Opportunity in Employment", 1945 December (Box 86)
    - Myrdal, Gunnar. "Mr. Gunnar Myrdal, at a Dinner Given in His Honor by the Committee of 100 at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel in New York, June 2, 1948", undated (Box 86)
    - Naill, Mahlon. Excerpt from a letter to Dorothy Norman, undated (Box 86)
    - Nehru, Jawaharlal. "Jawaharlal Nehru's Statement at His Trial Held in Gorakhpur Prison, November 3, 1940", undated (Box 86)
    - Newhall, Beaumont. "For Dorothy Norman's Stieglitz Portfolio", undated (Box 86)
    - Newhall, Nancy. "Alfred Stieglitz", 1946 July 22 (Box 86)
    - Nin, Anaïs. "Birth", undated (Box 86)
    - Nin, Anaïs. "From: Diary - Volume One (Age 11-12)", undated (Box 86)
    - Nin, Anaïs. "Woman in the Myth", undated (Box 86)
    - Nomad, Max. "The Kingdom of the Coming Cad", undated (Box 86)
    - Norman, Dorothy. "Angna Enters: First Person Plural", undated (Box 86)
    - Norman, Dorothy. "Dark Century in Never World", undated (Box 86)
    - Norman, Dorothy. "Dedication", undated (Box 86)
    - Norman, Dorothy. "A Dream", undated (Box 86)
    - Norman, Dorothy. "Edgar Varese: Ionizations - Espace", undated (Box 86)
    - Norman, Dorothy. "The Importance of the Right Angle: A Study of Angna Enters", undated (Box 86)
    - Norman, Dorothy. Notes on Sue Davidson Lowe's book on Alfred Stieglitz, Laurie Lisle's book on Georgia O'Keeffe, and Jan Castro's article on Alfred Stieglitz, 1983 (Box 86)
    - Norman, Dorothy. "On the Death of Hitler", undated (Box 86)
    - Norman, Dorothy. Poems, undated (Box 86)
    - Norman, Dorothy. "Political Rally - Election Eve - New York - Madison Square Garden - 1944-45", undated (Box 86)
    - Norman, Dorothy. "Stieglitz Died a Fighter for True Art", 1946 July 15 (Box 86)
    - Norman, Dorothy. "The Theatre of Angna Enters", undated (Box 86)
    - Norman, Dorothy. "Three Conversations About Alfred Stieglitz After His Death - 1946", undated (Box 86)
    - Norman, Dorothy. "Twice A Year", undated (Box 86)
    - Norman, Dorothy. "Two Conversations: Marcel Duchamp and Tristan Tzara", undated (Box 86)
    - Novalis. Unsorted writings, undated (Box 87)
    - O'Connor, Basil. "Constitutional Protection of the Alien's Right", undated (Box 87)
    - Odets, Clifford. "Notes From a Side Pocket", undated (Box 87)
    - Olson, Charles. "Dostoevsky and the Possessed", undated (Box 87)
    - Pach, Walter. "Translator's Note", undated (Box 87)
    - Padover, Saul. "Diary of Pre-Fascist Vienna", 1931? (Box 87)
    - Padover, Saul. Untitled, undated (Box 87)
    - Pandit, Chandralekha. "Wilful Murder", undated (Box 87)
    - Pandit, Chandralekha. "The Infanticide", undated (Box 87)
    - Pandit, Vitaya Lakshmi. Untitled, undated (Box 87)
    - Patchen, Kenneth. "Good Night and May God Bless You", undated (Box 87)
    - Patchen, Kenneth. "These Have Gone With Silent Hands, Seeking", undated (Box 87)
    - Peggram, Edwin Reed. "Andre Gide: Novelist", undated (Box 87)
    - Peggram, Edwin Reed. "Echoes in a Stone Rome", undated (Box 87)
    - Pereda, Prudencio de. "My Soul To Take," "My Soul To Give", undated (Box 87)
    - Perlès, Alfred. "Rainer Maria Rilke", undated (Box 87)
    - Perry, Leslie S. "Patterns of Discrimination in Fundamental Human Rights", undated (Box 87)
    - Philips, Duncan. "Contrasts of Impressionism", undated (Box 87)
    - Phillips, Marjorie. Untitled, undated (Box 87)
    - Pilpel, Harriet. "The Esquire Case", undated (Box 87)
    - Pink, Louis H. (Louis Heaton). "Sir William and the Senator", undated (Box 87)
    - Piscutor, Edwin. "A Dream in Wartime", 1941 June (Box 87)
    - Polejska, Frank. "Thought Variation", undated (Box 87)
    - Pollak, Franklin. "Decisions of the Supreme Court of the United States in the Field of Civil Liberties, 1939-1940", undated (Box 87)
    - Porter, Eliot. "A Few Words in Appreciation of Alfred Stieglitz", undated (Box 87)
    - Post, C. Gordon (Charles Gordon). "America - After the Peace", undated (Box 87)
    - Powell, Clarence Alva. "Finite", 1946, undated (Box 87)
    - Pozner, Vladimir. "Nation of Fishermen", undated (Box 87)
    - Proust, Marcel. "A Young Girl's Confession", undated (Box 87)